What I want you to do is on Say Love You, go ahead and the user page,
we had a bunch of users, go ahead and just make those things links that you can click.
So you can go to their specific ID and then show that user's basically data.
And don't worry about the nested routes bonus, but I mean,
if you happen to have the time, feel free to check that out.
The other part of the exercise I totally forgot is that you know, there's a login page.
Basically what I want you to do is just check to make sure that the user types an email in there,
just something basic, you don't need a full regex thing.
Maybe check like that the characters are greater than three and includes an at symbol.
And if that happens, then when they click login, allow the user to navigate over to another page.
So whether you want to navigate to the user's page, practice that programmatic navigation.
So the way this is going to work is we're going to go inside of our Say Love You.
Say Love You, I keep messing that up actually.
I see the Say Love You and then Run Dev.
Looks like we're good.
And then inside of Chrome, boom, there we are.
Oh, 74, I just realized, because I have two running.
Great.
OK.
So the exercise here was to go into the login and start by programmatically navigating it somewhere.
So inside of our source, inside of our views, we're going to look at our login page.
And all right, we're just basically going to do a quick check to make sure we actually have an email.
So again, when I do anything too fancy here, we're just going to v-model to something called,
let's say, user, or let's say, email input.
That's what I'll call it.
And so I'll import a ref from view, because this is something we want to track.
And so we'll say cons email input equals ref, that is an empty string by default.
So to show that this works, though, I'll do 1, 2, 3.
You'll notice that it does populate up.
So that's fine.
We know that it's working.
The thing we need to check, though, is that when the user clicks here and we'll call this login,
so cons login, we need to actually make sure that email input actually has the thing, right?
So log test, whoops, not test.
So we'll log email input dot value.
And so to show what I mean by this is we can see here, if I go Ben at Ben, then we can continue with email.
You'll see that that is actually being rendered out as expected.
OK, great.
So now all we need to do is just do a simple check to say, if email dot input dot value, let's say, so this is a string, right?
So I think we actually can do that includes an at symbol.
And the email input dot value dot length is greater than 3.
We'll just keep the logic simple here.
Then we'll say valid user.
Else log invalid user.
OK, let's see if that works.
We have test, nothing's working at, huh, nothing is working.
Why? Because, well, we didn't click on anything.
There you go.
That's a valid user.
If we just do test invalid user because there's no at symbol.
But then we just do at by itself also invalid user.
OK, easy enough as an email test.
Again, just so you know, this is not production grade quality email validation.
Just know this is just for demo purposes.
We have our valid user.
So what do we want to do?
We want to navigate it.
We want to navigate our users to a page.
How do we do that?
Well, let's go ahead and import our use router from view router.
Then we will go ahead and construct it by calling it our router using use router.
And then all we need to do is inside here.
We'll just leave the console log because that's nice to have for now.
As you router that push and let's go to user just like that.
And so whoops, something's not happy.
What's going on?
Well, I have typos up here at the top.
That's what's wrong.
Let's save here much better.
OK, so we do the T and then we continue with email.
Nothing's happening.
Great.
Test at email.com.
Continue with email.
Look at that programmatic navigation.
Easy peasy with the composition API in that we imported it.
Use the router to set it up.
And then we just push the user once we had fulfilled our logic for the app.
OK, the final thing that we need to do is that we need the user to be able to
actually look at different things.
So when we click on it, they'll actually be able to at least see user one, user two.
Or in this case, we actually might even just want to show their name.
Let's do that.
So the way we might do that is we'll go inside of our routes.
So I think it's in.
Oh, kind of we're managing it inside of here.
That's totally fine.
So we'll basically create a user page.
Well, it looks like I didn't use name that quite well.
So what I'm going to do for now just to make it a little bit easier is I'm
going to call it user detail page.
But you should note that user page is slightly semantically inaccurate.
So the h1 here will be our user.
So I'll just say user name so it's easy to see that we switched pages.
And then we have our path to slash user slash.
And then this time we'll call the variable name instead of id to show you how that works.
Component will import what?
Will import slash views slash user detail page.view save.
OK, to show that this works, we'll go inside of our user page.
And inside of each of these loops, rather than just having the card here, what we're
going to do is we're going to actually wrap it here inside of a router link too.
And so the router card will just go inside of our router link.
And what we're going to route it to is going to be a JavaScript.
We're going to dynamically bind this one because we need to dynamically create it,
which is going to be slash user slash.
And then we'll do the basically user dot name.
This might be a little bit tricky, though, because I know there are spaces in here.
OK, so if we refresh this, ooh, did not like that user.
Oh, right, because the loop is in here.
So my mistake, we actually cannot do it at this level.
At least the way it's currently architected, I would need to actually go inside
of user card in order to actually do this.
So inside of here is where then we would actually then say, OK, wrap this in a router link.
And inside of here is where we can say to ES6 template slash user slash user dot name,
just like that.
There you go.
We see our link showing up now.
Wonderful.
So if we inspect all of these, we'll see that we can see slash liangram.
Great.
So if we click on it, we should see, oh, we are correctly being navigated to username.
So that's good.
But we need to actually make sure this shows up in a way that actually takes into account
the actual user's name.
So how do we do that?
Well, we need to get info on the route.
So where are we going to reach for?
We're reaching for use route from view router.
And then we'll initialize the route by calling use route.
And then we can basically log the route.params to show you what's happening here.
And you'll notice that inside of here, we have a name, because that's what we named
it inside of our routes.
So now that we have that, great.
All we need to do now is just swap it out to go route.params.name.
Save, choo, choo, choo, choo.
And there we have it.
So we've got user again, Irvin Clementine.
It works.
Question?
What if you wanted to pass that user object to the profile page and have
additional information that is not on that user's list page?
That is a great question.
So what I want you to check out for this, so the question here is around the fact
that what if you actually want to pass that user information to the route,
right, some sort of props passing that kind of stuff?
I believe it's in, I believe it's actually in the program.
Oh, passing props to rock components, literally this page.
So this will allow you to do kind of some interesting stuff regarding how you
pass parameters.
But what's interesting too is that if you turn certain routes as props true,
it'll actually drop the parameters and certain things as props to the page.
So you don't even need to use use route.
It'll actually be passed as a prop to the component, which again takes a little
wrapping your mind around.
So it's one of those kind of intermediate to advanced techniques that if it's
something you're looking for, take a read of this document and see if it fits
your scenario.
But generally speaking, what we've been doing thus far regarding just grabbing
the route.pramsid, that fulfills, I would say, a good 70% to 80% of the use cases
out there, which is what I wanted to make sure that we covered.
Are you going to get burnt by deep linking to that page?
Deep linking to the page.
Passing in props, an object through the link, and you deep link to it,
without having visited the page before that, does that burn you?
That's where the state management can be very tricky.
So that's why you have to be careful when you're passing that kind of stuff
around, what stuff is already accessible.
Because earlier during the exercise, if you all noticed, when I loaded the home
page for sale of you, the five users actually don't show up.
So if I refresh this page, you'll notice it's gone.
And the reason for that, it's not a bug, actually.
It's how it's intended, because user page is what's actually loading the data.
And so unless you visit the user page, home page has no idea what these five
things are.
And so as far as the state's concern, the composable's concern, it doesn't exist.
So knowing where to import, how to make sure they stay in sync,
that's part of the puzzle of the game that we play.